<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-26T10:24:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PBCore Metadata Standard</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New PBCore Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/16/new-pbcore-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New PBCore Website" /><published>2018-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/16/new-pbcore-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/11/16/new-pbcore-website.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new PBCore website! Thanks to the NEH-funded PBCore Development and Training Project, PBCore has a new look and a number of new tools and features designed to make it more usable and accessible to the archival and public media communities.
&lt;span class=&quot;end-blurb&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re just getting started with PBCore, or want to learn more about the basics, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/what-is-pbcore.html&quot;&gt;What Is PBCore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/faq.html&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/glossary.html&quot;&gt;Glossary&lt;/a&gt; to learn about PBCore’s basic functionality and implementation, as well as get a handle on key terms used throughout the site. You can see all elements, with their definitions, on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/elements.html&quot;&gt;Elements&lt;/a&gt; page; view attributes with their definitions on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/attribute.html&quot;&gt;Attributes&lt;/a&gt; page; and see PBCore’s supported controlled vocabularies on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/pbcore-controlled-vocabularies.html&quot;&gt;Controlled Vocabularies&lt;/a&gt; page. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/xsd.html&quot;&gt;PBCore XML Schema&lt;/a&gt; page provides an overview on PBCore’s structure and revisions from PBCore 2.0 to PBCore 2.1, as well as a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WGBH/PBCore_2.1/&quot;&gt;PBCore GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re already familiar with PBCore, check out our new pages and features, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/cataloging-tool.html&quot;&gt;PBCore Cataloging Tool&lt;/a&gt;, a web app created by Digital Bedrock that supports the creation, editing, and export of moving image-related metadata as PBCore XML records&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/spreadsheet-templates.html&quot;&gt;PBCore Spreadsheet Templates&lt;/a&gt;, designed to capture PBCore metadata in an easy human-readable format for inventory or database import&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/validator.html&quot;&gt;PBCore Validator&lt;/a&gt;, which checks the validity and provides best practice recommendations for PBCore XML documents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated integrations with &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/external-tools-and-integrations.html&quot;&gt;external tools&lt;/a&gt;, including MediaInfo and ProTrack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/mappings.html&quot;&gt;Mappings&lt;/a&gt; to and from additional metadata standards, including MARC, Dublin Core, MODS, PREMIS, and EBUCore RDF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/sample-records.html&quot;&gt;sample records&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/tutorials.html&quot;&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt; covering everything from the basic structure of PBCore to how to design a PBCore-compliant database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/pbcore-users.html&quot;&gt;Case studies&lt;/a&gt; highlighting how different institutions implement the PBCore standard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collected &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/annual-meeting-notes.html&quot;&gt;annual meeting notes&lt;/a&gt; from 2015 on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the PBCore Development and Training Project continues, we’ll be adding more content to the site, including more video tutorials, updated external tool integrations, information about upcoming workshops, and more. We’d also love to feature more case studies and sample records, so please &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/contact.html&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you have any PBCore-related content that you’d like to share!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who’s made the new website possible, including the PBCore Development and Training Project Advisory Board; Dr. Rong Tang and the Simmons Usability Lab; and the WGBH Creative team. The old site remains live at &lt;v2.pbcore.org&gt;&lt;/v2.pbcore.org&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to the new PBCore website! Thanks to the NEH-funded PBCore Development and Training Project, PBCore has a new look and a number of new tools and features designed to make it more usable and accessible to the archival and public media communities.</summary></entry></feed>